geocities.com 1999-10-12

# Yahoo! Privacy Policy

|  GeoCities Statement on Privacy -  _for members and visitors_

* * *

**Dear Community Members,**

GeoCities provides interactive environments on the Internet to enable and encourage members to express themselves and share their interests by creating diverse, high-quality content within themed virtual communities. 

The resulting high traffic, the passionate involvement of our members and our expertise in building and managing these communities enable the company to offer a broad range of commercial services. 

GeoCities is an amazing place. More than a million people from all six livable continents, and over 200 countries have taken up residence in one of our neighborhoods. In addition to having over 1.6 million members, we receive over 90 million visits a month by 9 million unique visitors, and are one of the five most visited sites on the Internet. We respect our position a leader in the Internet industry and our responsibility to set examples that will frame the standards for others on the Web. 

GeoCities has been fortunate to attract major advertisers and sponsors who are primarily responsible for allowing us to provide all of the services and features we offer and will offer in the future. We understand, and our sponsors understand, that our success and their success are dependent on the goodwill of our homesteaders and visitors. 

To promote trust and confidence in the Internet and in GeoCities, we are providing a full disclosure of our privacy practices and information uses. We encourage all other Internet organizations to do the same and/or to endorse and use our Statement on Privacy. 

One of our main goals at GeoCities is to respect the privacy rights of anyone who joins GeoCities or visits any of our neighborhoods. Except as set forth within this privacy statement and within the scope of our community and content guidelines, we will never release personally identifiable information about our individual members and visitors without their permission. 

Our view is that our members and users are the ones who should generally control whether or not they share any personal information and how that information is used if it is shared. Furthermore, we believe that it is our responsibility to provide something of value in exchange for any information shared - in our case, free personal home pages, e-mail, chat rooms and other free services. 

Furthermore, we actively support various Web and industry efforts to establish policies and standards in the areas of cookies, user information and privacy. 

We appreciate your interest in and support of GeoCities and pledge to you our continued support in building the "Societies of the New Frontier." 

For information about how to contact GeoCities about technical problems, to report a violation of our guidelines, advertising within our domain, or any other item of interest or concern, please visit our Contact Page: [ http://www.geocities.com/main/contact/](http://www.geocities.com/main/contact/). 

GeoCities respects the privacy of all those who spend any amount of time in our communities. We do collect information from our members and visitors. This is a statement of the use of the information that we collect, and if or how any of it is disseminated. 

**_David Bohnett and the Staff of GeoCities_**

_Last modified April 10, 1998_

* * *

**GeoCities and the Privacy of our Visitors and Members**

|   
1. | 
* **What information do we compile and use? And what methods do we use to collect information?**     We give notice to everyone prior to collecting any personally identifiable information. Such personally identifiable information will be used only for the purposes stated at the time of collection, and within this Web document. 

GeoCities does not share any personally identifiable information with outside parties for commercial purposes, unless stated at the time of collection. The option is given, at the time of collection, not to allow GeoCities to share such information with outside parties. If such an option is taken, we will not share such information with outside parties; however, we do reserve the right to release that information concerning a member, when the member partakes in an illegal activity, or for a member who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. GeoCities hopes that all third parties involved adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our members; however, GeoCities does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. 

For everyone who visits the GeoCities domain, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that the visitor's computer uses, and the type of browser software used by the visitor. From the IP address, we can determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of the visitor's point of connectivity. 

We use the aggregate data we collect to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our members and visitors, to measure overall patron demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the GeoCities domain and to analyze how and where to use our resources. We also use the aggregate data collected, to inform our sponsors as to numbers of people who have seen and "clicked" on their advertisement. We also use cookies to help us determine how long users view particular content, what particular content (e.g. advertising) users view, what content or sites users link to, and what GeoCities services members and visitors use. 

Currently, GeoCities is using cookies, and, as with all online companies who do, we are continuously evaluating our use of this information. As we have previously stated, we actively support various Web and industry efforts to establish policies and standards in the areas of cookies, user information and privacy.   
  
---|---  
  
  * **What are cookies and what are you using them for?**  
     A "cookie" is a file transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website can track your activities on the website. A cookie will not let a website know any personally identifying information about you, such as your real name, address, etc., unless you previously provided that information at the website or have set your preferences in your browser to provide that information. GeoCities is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. The coding in the cookies we set lets us know that you are a particular user, but nothing more. We may, in the future, use cookies to help personalize GeoCities for individual members so that it will seem even more like "Your Home on the Web." 

Cookies are a way for us to track who has seen which pages on our site, who has seen which ads, how often some pages are visited, and what the most popular areas of GeoCities are. 

  * **Why do we need this information?**  
     GeoCities uses cookies in order to help serve you better. Without cookies it would be difficult for GeoCities to know that certain neighborhoods are more popular than others. This information helps us to better understand when to open up new neighborhoods or suburbs of existing neighborhoods. Cookies also help us know whether or not users have seen particular banners, including advertising, so we don't bore you with the same advertisement over and over again. 

Do we think cookies can be annoying and a distraction? Yes, many of us within GeoCities have cookies turned off on our browsers, and if a site tries to set cookies too many times, we may get discouraged and are less likely to return. In this, we are assuming that most people who visit GeoCities feel the same way we do. 

  * **Do we have to use cookies to determine this information?**  
     To date, cookies are the most effective method of collecting the data that is helpful to GeoCities. Are we concerned about a negative backlash from our members and visitors if we use cookies? Absolutely, and if it turns out that we can't find a way to make this work, then we'll have to look at some other alternative. 

|  The bottom line is that, with the help of our members and visitors, we think that we will find ways to address the issues involved with the usage of cookies and a lot of other issues within our communities. GeoCities is constantly evolving, and is never finished. We value kindness, friendship and helping people. With your help and the help of your fellow homesteaders, we'll develop community policies and procedures that keep this whole community growing and thriving. 

We do not monitor the use of e-mail accounts, unless prompted by a request from a legal authority or in instances in which the activities of the user is interfering in the daily operation of GeoCities. We do use the information provided in the registration process as we have set forth within this privacy statement and within the scope of our community and content guidelines. 

In our chat rooms, we do collect all logins and dialogue. The logs are kept for an indeterminate amount of time. We do not perform any analysis of this information. 

We do not collect any e-mail addresses of those who communicate with GeoCities via e-mail. We only use the information provided so that we may respond to the e-mail. 

When GeoCities sponsors promotions or sweepstakes, it will post privacy information contained in the rules and /or login area for the promotion or sweepstakes, which, to the extent it conflicts with this statement, will govern that particular promotion or sweepstakes. Anyone else conducting promotions or sweepstakes within GeoCities must adhere to our privacy statement and divulge how any information collected will be used. We do not allow our homesteaders to use GeoCities for the purpose of gathering personally identifiable information for commercial or unlawful purposes. 

GeoCities does not control the acts of its members and visitors. All members and visitors should be aware that, when they disclose personal information such as their actual name, member name, e-mail address, etc., on their webpage, in a newsgroup, guestbook, chat room or forum, the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside GeoCities. In the event that you encounter any GeoCities homesteader who is improperly collecting or using information about users, please contact [abuse@geocities.com](mailto:%20abuse@geocities.com).   
  
---|---  

3. |  **How do we disseminate the information we collect?**     During the registration process for GeoCities membership, an individual is presented with the choice of whether or not to receive promotional information from GeoCities or our sponsors. For those who elect to receive promotional materials from GeoCities or third parties, and who indicate that they do in their profile, we do release personally identifiable information. Information released includes: real name, street address, e-mail address, interests, GeoCities neighborhood, and the broader personal information (e.g., level of education, occupation and marital status) supplied in the GeoCities registration and personal profile. If the member is under the age of 13, we will not release any personally identifiable information, even if the child indicates on his or her registration or personal profile that he or she would like to receive such information. 

GeoCities limits the sending or e-mail solicitations to members who have requested this type of information/communication. Such solicitations are limited in that they, among other things, must clearly indicate who the originator of the e-mail is, and provide the member with a method of opting out from receiving future communications. 

If you are receiving e-mail from a third party who states that it is specifically associated with GeoCities, yet you indicated on your registration or profile editor that you did not want to receive promotional material from GeoCities or its sponsors, please first attempt to follow the third party's removal procedures. Then verify that your personal profile is correct. If it is incorrect or does indeed indicate that you chose to not receive the e-mail, please contact us at: [geoprivacy@geocities.com](mailto:geoprivacy@geocities.com), and we will promptly investigate why this error occurred. 

GeoCities does not sell or lease personally identifiable information regarding GeoCities homesteaders who elect in their registration form or on their personal profile not to receive promotional materials from third parties. 

GeoCities encourages all third parties involved to adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our members, but GeoCities does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. 

If, at any time, you decide that you would like to change your indication of whether to receive or not to receive promotional information from GeoCities or its sponsors, you need only change your personal profile to indicate your choice: [ http://www.geocities.com/members/tools/profile_editor.html](http://www.geocities.com/members/tools/profile_editor.html)

We respond to subpoenas, warrants, or other court orders regarding information that is contained within our access logs, concerning any member or visitor. We also reserve the right to release that information concerning a member who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. We cooperate with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who use our servers for illegal activities. We also reserve the right to report any illegal activity to law enforcement for prosecution.   
  
---|---  

7. |  **In which ways may I protect my privacy on the Internet and within GeoCities?**
*  **Know the risks.**  
When you communicate with others online, you should be aware that, when disclosing personal information such as one's actual name, member name, e-mail address, etc., on a webpage, in a newsgroup, chat room or forum, that information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside GeoCities. Some of the e-mail you receive may be useful to you, but some may not be. GeoCities cannot prevent information gathering robots called "harvesters" from traversing our domain, but in an effort to curtail unsolicited e-mail, we do block certain e-mail addresses and domains from sending e-mail to e-mail addresses at our domain. 

You should also be aware that, although GeoCities respects the privacy of your e-mail messages, it makes no representation, warranties or commitments concerning our ability to keep your e-mail messages private. 

* **Educate yourself.**  
Search the Web for as much information as you can about how to protect your privacy. Look for a privacy statement in the sites you visit. Some places to start include:   
    SiliconValley/Vista/6001 \- Practical Privacy Issues (available in English and Russian) 
* **Tell your children: "Never talk to strangers!"**  
Tell them to not give out their names or other personal information. They should also be instructed not to fill out any forms or register at any domain without your knowledge and consent. 
* **Use PGP (Pretty Good Privacy)[http://www.pgp.com](http://www.pgp.com/) or another encryption program.**
* **Understand the relative ease involved in cracking a password.**  
Recognize, too, the necessity of inconvenience when passwords are involved, such as when you have to enter passwords with weird characters with those very long and awkward keystroke combinations.   
---|---  
  
"Hackers pose a real threat to everyone. Using programs that continually guess at user names and password combinations, hackers can literally search 24 hours a day to get what they want. If a password is made up of eight characters using only lowercase letters of the alphabet, that limits the search to just 208 billion possibilities. Sound astronomical? It's not. At 100,000 guesses per second, the most rudimentary hacking program can crack this kind of password in about three weeks. 

But suppose that eight character password were made up of both upper- and lowercase letters, and included numerals and other special characters (like the dollar sign or ampersand). The possibilities for an eight character password would soar to 722 trillion. And the time it takes to crack them: 229 years!" 

|  The above quoted information is taken from: [http://www.usc.edu/go/networker/97-98/ Sep_Oct_97/dispatch-passwords.html](http://www.usc.edu/go/networker/97-98/Sep_Oct_97/dispatch-passwords.html)

We do not give out passwords to anyone, except the e-mail registered with a given homepage. 

To prevent access to your GeoCities account by anyone who should not have access, NEVER give your password out to anyone. If someone claims to represent GeoCities in an e-mail or a chatroom and asks for your GeoCities password, do not honor the request. We never ask for passwords, except on our site in the places you need to access our system --- file manager, special promotional opportunities, profile editor, etc.   
  
---|---  
  
* * *

If you feel that GeoCities has violated this Statement on Privacy in any way, please contact us at: [geoprivacy@geocities.com](mailto:geoprivacy@geocities.com), so that we may address this issue. 

* * *

**In closing, we appreciate your interest and support of GeoCities, and we welcome you to our community.**

* * *

| 
Yahoo! is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. 

[](https://www.truste.org/validate/361) **TRUSTe Certified**

Yahoo! is TRUSTe-certified. This certification applies to all English-language sites under the Yahoo.com domain. Please keep in mind that some of the products or services mentioned specifically in this policy may not be available on all of our international Yahoo! sites at this time. 

This policy will let you know: 

1\. What personally identifiable information is collected from you;  
2\. What cookies are and how they are used;   
3\. How your information is used;   
4\. Who is collecting your information;   
5\. With whom your information may be shared;   
6\. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information;  
7\. How you can access, update or delete your information;  
8\. How Yahoo! treats your personal financial and health-related information;  
9\. The kind of security precautions that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of your information;  
10\. How Yahoo! protects children's privacy; and  
11\. What else you should know about your online privacy.  

* * *

**NOTICE:[Click here](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/online/sitesee/index.html) for important information about safe surfing from the Federal Trade Commission.**

* * *

**What personally identifiable information does Yahoo! collect from me?**

Yahoo! collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites. 

Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, Yahoo! asks for your name, email address, birth date, gender, zip code, occupation, industry and personal interests. The more information you volunteer (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to customize your experience. Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Yahoo! - you are given a Yahoo! ID and are able to take full advantage of Yahoo!'s many offerings. 

In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by Yahoo! and/or our many partners; when you make a purchase using Yahoo! Shopping; when you make travel arrangements using Yahoo! Travel; when you post a Yahoo! Classified ad; when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact Yahoo! we may keep a record of that correspondence. Yahoo! also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever Yahoo! collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

* * *

**What are cookies and how does Yahoo! use them?**

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Yahoo! uses [cookies](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/cookie.htm) to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All sites on Yahoo! where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies. (See "What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?" for more information on cookies.) 

Generally, we use cookies to: 

(1) Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services. Yahoo! also uses cookies to store your zip code for other services, such as Yellow Pages. 

(2) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Yahoo! is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior. 

(3) Assist merchants in Yahoo! Stores to track visits to and business at their stores, and to process the items in your shopping basket. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "clickstream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen in each merchant's store. 

(4) Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes and contests. When a Yahoo!-hosted promotion uses cookies, the information written to the cookie indicates the player's progress through the promotion, and may be used to track entries, submissions, and status in prize drawings. 

(5) Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Yahoo!'s network of web sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Yahoo! a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites. 

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Yahoo! may also use their own cookies. 

Yahoo! also collects [IP addresses](http://www.zdwebopedia.com/TERM/I/IP_address.html) for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, Yahoo! Mail includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers. 

* * *

**How does Yahoo! use my information?**

Yahoo!'s primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our network of sites. This includes personalization services, interactive communications, online shopping and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, Yahoo! is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. 

In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, Yahoo! plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach (for example, males over 35 years old). Yahoo! takes the advertisement and displays it to users meeting that criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only Yahoo! has access to individuals' accounts. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads as well as promotional email through Yahoo! Delivers. You will only receive special offers via email from Yahoo! if you have indicated in your account preferences that you would like to receive them. You can change your account preferences at any time. 

Yahoo! does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. Yahoo! may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners. 

* * *

**Who is collecting information?**

When you are on a Yahoo! site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Yahoo! alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. For example, some Yahoo! services, like Yahoo! Travel, are offered in conjunction with a partner company. In order to provide this co-branded service to you, it is necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner company. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Yahoo!, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Promotions that run on Yahoo! may be sponsored by companies other than Yahoo! or may be cosponsored by Yahoo! and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared. Currently, most Yahoo! promotions are limited to US or North American residents. 

Please be aware that Yahoo! advertisers or web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. The information practices of those web sites linked to Yahoo! are not covered by this privacy statement. 

* * *

**With whom does Yahoo! share my information?**

As a general rule, Yahoo! will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. 

_Business Partners & Sponsors_: Yahoo! may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Service or Use Agreements, and sweepstakes and promotions rules. Some or all data collected during a Yahoo! promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If personally identifying data about you will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. 

Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give Yahoo! permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer. 

_Yahoo! Stores & Shopping_: If you make a purchase from a store hosted by Yahoo! Store, or a merchant in Yahoo! Shopping, the information obtained during your visit to those stores, and the information you give such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to the merchants. This is to enable transactions to take place. 

Merchants listed in Yahoo! Shopping or site or in Yahoo! Stores have separate privacy and data collection practices. Yahoo! has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their **Information** link. 

_Yahoo! Auctions_ : On the Yahoo! Auctions site, we currently provide the information necessary to facilitate the auction transaction between the buyer and the seller. 

_Yahoo! GeoCities_ : If you have a personal home page on Yahoo! GeoCities you may choose to participate in the Pages That Pay program. If you sign up to become an affiliate with this program, Yahoo! will share certain personal information of yours with BeFree, Inc. and each merchant you select. This includes information from the affiliate application and a unique Yahoo! GeoCities identifier number. This information is transmitted in order for you to participate in the program and to receive compensation for the sales and traffic to the merchants' sites generated from your web site. For more detailed information about the Pages That Pay program, please [click here](http://geocities.yahoo.com/pagesthatpay/ptp_market.html). 

From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Yahoo! will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them . 

_Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate_: Under confidentiality agreements, Yahoo! may match user information with third party data. Also, Yahoo! discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users are female) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

_Other:_ Yahoo! may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating Yahoo!'s Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Yahoo!'s rights or property, other Yahoo! users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Yahoo! may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services. 

* * *

**What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**

Yahoo! may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Yahoo! and our partners, we may occasionally send you direct mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only Yahoo! (or agents working on behalf of Yahoo! and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily edit your [Yahoo! Account Information](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/set_profile) to no longer receive such offers and mailings. You will need your Yahoo! ID and Password in order to access your [Yahoo! Account Information](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/set_profile). 

On some types of Yahoo! promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related email, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements. 

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Yahoo! services that require registration in order to participate. These services include (but are not limited to): Yahoo! Mail, My Yahoo!, Calendar, Chat, Message Boards, and creating a portfolio in Yahoo! Finance. You can still use Yahoo! Shopping and Yahoo! Auctions and many other Yahoo! sites even if you do not accept cookies. 

Yahoo! does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests. 

* * *

**What is Yahoo!'s policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?**

You may edit your [Yahoo! Account Information](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/set_profile) and your public [Yahoo! Profile](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/edit_identity) at any time by using your Yahoo! ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please [click here](http://edit.yahoo.com/config/eval_forgot_pw) to request a new password. For all other problems signing in to Yahoo!, please [click here](http://add.yahoo.com/fast/help/edit/cgi_change) and complete this form. 

Your Yahoo! account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so will result in not being able to access any members-only area of the Yahoo! network, including your Yahoo! Mail account (if you have one). If you saved the confirmation email you received when you first created your Yahoo! account, you can use the URL provided in that message to delete your account at any time. Please contact [privacypolicy@yahoo-inc.com](mailto:privacypolicy@yahoo-inc.com) for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your Yahoo! account. 

If you are participating in a Yahoo! promotion and you wish to update your email address on the promotions mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related email, please contact [promotions-feedback@yahoo-inc.com](mailto:promotions-feedback@yahoo-inc.com). 

* * *

**How does Yahoo! protect my personal financial and health-related information?**

Keeping your personal financial and health-related information private is vitally important to us. As with all information, Yahoo! will never rent or sell your personal financial or health-related information. This includes information kept in your Yahoo! Portfolio or from any Yahoo! Health assessment tools. For more specific information about health-related data, please see the [Yahoo! Health Data Privacy and Security Policy](http://health.yahoo.com/health/dataprivacy.html). 

If you use Yahoo! Online Banking Access, Yahoo! will work with your financial institution to present your account balances and history to you on your customized Yahoo! pages. In order to present your financial information to you, Yahoo! receives that information from your financial institution in an encrypted format and presents it to you over a secure-server. Yahoo! Online Banking Access is regularly updated. Yahoo! encrypts this data and stores it on our secure servers. 

Knowing that you use certain services or features may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial product or service usage on Yahoo! are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user. 

Please note that there are several places on the Yahoo! network of Web sites where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes. Any time we ask for a credit card number we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. 

* * *

**What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**

Your Yahoo! Account Information and Yahoo! Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your [Yahoo! Account Information](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/set_profile) and [Yahoo! Profile](http://edit.my.yahoo.com/config/edit_identity) by using your Yahoo! ID and password. 

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Yahoo! will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your Yahoo! account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

As a global company Yahoo! has international sites and users all over the world. When you give Yahoo! personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information, such as to the United States or other countries. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever Yahoo! handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, Yahoo! takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Yahoo! cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

* * *

**What about children's privacy?**

Naturally, the safety of children is very important to us. Yahoo! recommends that parents and kids try Yahooligans!, a web guide designed especially for users between the ages of 7 and 12. Sites listed on Yahooligans! have all been selected by a team of experienced educators. This selection process ensures that these sites are fun and age-appropriate for our younger audience. Yahooligans! does not collect personally identifiable information from children. 

Yahoo! is a general audience web site. When children under age 13 attempt to register with Yahoo!, we ask them to have a parent or guardian establish a Yahoo! Family Account. The Family Accounts feature allows Yahoo! to obtain verifiable consent from a parent or guardian before we collect any registration information from a child we know to be under 13 years of age. In addition, Family Accounts allow a parent to access their child's Yahoo! account, edit account information and better control their child's personal information. To learn more about Yahoo! Family Accounts, please see our [Yahoo! Family Accounts](http://family.yahoo.com/) page. 

Children should always ask a parent for permission before sending personal information to anyone online. Yahoo! does not share personal information about users under the age of 13 with third parties and we do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age. In addition, Yahoo! will not send any direct email offers to users who indicate they are under the age of 13. 

* * *

**What else should I know about my privacy?**

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

* * *

**Additional Information**

Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [privacypolicy@yahoo-inc.com](mailto:privacypolicy@yahoo-inc.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement or if your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/users/watchdog.html). 

**Also see...**

  * [Electronic Frontier Foundation](http://www.eff.org/) \- a civil liberties organization working to protect your rights online. 
  * [Electronic Privacy Information Center](http://epic.org/) \- established to focus public attention on emerging civil liberties issues relating to the National Information Infrastructure. 
  * [Privacy Issues Page](http://www.cdt.org/privacy/) \- from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT). 
  * [The EPIC Cookies Page](http://www.epic.org/privacy/internet/cookies/) \- definitions, links, and news. 
  * [How to Protect Your Privacy](http://www.ftc.gov/privacy/index.html) \- information from the Federal Trade Commission. 
  * [Yahoo! et votre vie prive](http://www.yahoo.fr/docs/ref/frprivacy.html) \- Yahoo!'s privacy policy in French. 
  * [Was Yahoo! zum Datenschutz unternimmt](http://www.yahoo.de/docs/info/mail/datenschutz.html) \- Yahoo!'s privacy policy in German.
